WILLIAMS AJAYI BALOGUN

Frontend Developer

- https://williamsbalogun.netlify.app
- th https://linkedin.com/in/williamsbalogun
- https://github.com/willhemz
- ## https://twitter.com/king_hayjhay?t=NQhyW25e51IwiPa1lOcC1g&s=09
- ⊠ williamsbalogun49@gmail.com
- **Q** Lagos, Nigeria.

SUMMARY

Experienced Frontend Developer with proficiency in utilizing high end stacks in creating quality websites and web applications. Open-source contributor, facilitator, open to challenges, ably solid in engaging and collaborating with other developers, designers, product managers.

EDUCATION

Obafemi Awolowo University

2016 - 2022

B.Sc. Mechanical Engineering (CGPA 4.03/5.00)

Class Rank: Top 10%

Undergraduate Research – "Numerical Study on the Heat Transfer Enhancement in Straight and Wavy Microchannel Heat Sinks Under Pulsating CuO-Al2O3/H2O Hybrid Nanofluid"

EXPERIENCE

HNG Frontend Intern at Zuri

October – December (2022)

- Collaborated with several Developers (Frontend, Backend), DevOps, Designers and Product Manager to building web solutions to problems. Most notable are:
 - https://coverly.app
 - https://streetrates.info

Freelance Developer

2021 - 2022

- Worked with a few clients and developers in building, modifying and restructuring their web sites and web applications.

- Volunteered and collaborated in the development of a shopping websites for a startup company (https://umecarts.com)
- Volunteered and collaborated in the development of a website containing designs catalogs for Delta Computers & Stores Ltd (https://newdcstech.com)

Staff 2012 – 2016

- Worked in the training department to tutor trainees on the use of Microsoft Office Applications and also helped them boost their typing skills.
- Was Head of Training in 2013 through 2014. Managed trainees' welfare.
- Worked in the operations department as a Graphics Designer. Created designs (booklets, magazines, logo, ID cards, complementary cards, calendars, shirt designs etc.) for individuals, brands, schools, organizations and government bodies etc.
- Was Head of Operations in 2015. Managed all jobs from our clients and ensured tasks are duly assigned and deadlines were met. Ensured clients got satisfaction from jobs delivered.

TECHNOLOGIES

• JavaScript • jQuery • React • Redux

Axios
Tailwind
Bootstrap
Material UI

SassFirebaseJasmine

TOOLS

GitTerminalGithubNetlify

Vercel
Slack
Linear
Discord

• Twitter • Zoom

PROJECTS

Personal Projects

- https://ihemz-cocktail.netlify.app

- https://ihemz-stripe.netlify.app

- https://ihemz-grocery.netlify.app

- https://ihemz-dolapot.netlify.app

Collaborative Projects

- https://streetrates.app

- https://coverly.app

- https://newdcstech.com

- https://umecarts.com